<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Source Themes | Dr. Xiaotao Shen</title>
    <link>https://www.shenxt.info/tags/source-themes/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.shenxt.info/tags/source-themes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Source Themes</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Xiaotao Shen 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Reaction Network-based Recursive Metabolite Annotation for Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Large-scale metabolite annotation is a challenge in liquid chromatogram-mass spectrometry (LC-MS)-based untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop a metabolic reaction network (MRN)-based recursive algorithm (MetDNA) that expands metabolite annotations without the need for a comprehensive standard spectral library. MetDNA is based on the rationale that seed metabolites and their reaction-paired neighbors tend to share structural similarities resulting in similar MS2 spectra. MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small library of MS2 spectra, and utilizes their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites, which subsequently serve as the basis for recursive analysis. Using different LC-MS platforms, data acquisition methods, and biological samples, we showcase the utility and versatility of MetDNA and demonstrate that about 2000 metabolites can cumulatively be annotated from one experiment. Our results demonstrate that MetDNA substantially expands metabolite annotation, enabling quantitative assessment of metabolic pathways and facilitating integrative multi-omics analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow an interactive and integrated workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metnormalizer_metabolomics_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metnormalizer_metabolomics_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;availability-and-implementation&#34;&gt;Availability and implementation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MetFlow is freely available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://metflow.zhulab.cn/&#34;&gt;http://metflow.zhulab.cn/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supplementary-information&#34;&gt;Supplementary information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oup.silverchair-cdn.com/oup/backfile/Content_public/Journal/bioinformatics/PAP/10.1093_bioinformatics_bty1066/4/bty1066_supp.docx?Expires=1562370413&amp;amp;Signature=M~uVkc2HM8lV5SS96cccuCh4ZGmq3t5Y3m6X5UCE85GL6tLSiZh5YderYebpfDOwuKWwA9xMxzosXVrwU7f5l314XM6FtEfdChq7YK50O0UReaExGH7LSDTF9yrr0otobCobxejF9MaLttvPhTSV1u2R-~q3n~uqRA-sMZWF2TDaSWo2s-f6E2dknkx5aYgPa56R1MrSbzG1Eu95NCXBGh56Q6-uaCMn6zuwEnzDnKgvONbm0lHjZsO7HhYZJ3evbZ-OsFJiuGpzgpaXoV2OUdL71sCdqm9ebAlPdiNVTGa7T~iUXRBc4vUvmvPcU0eBNoHo3teCF2fC3I0wA03cSQ__&amp;amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAIE5G5CRDK6RD3PGA&#34;&gt;Supplementary data&lt;/a&gt; are available at Bioinformatics online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow an interactive and integrated workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass spectrometry-based metabolomics aims to profile the metabolic changes in biological systems and identify differential metabolites related to physiological phenotypes and aberrant activities. However, many confounding factors during data acquisition complicate metabolomics data, which is characterized by high dimensionality, uncertain degrees of missing and zero values, nonlinearity, unwanted variations and non-normality. Therefore, prior to differential metabolite discovery analysis, various types of data cleaning such as batch alignment, missing value imputation, data normalization and scaling are essentially required for data post-processing. Here, we developed an interactive web server, namely, MetFlow, to provide an integrated and comprehensive workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
