<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zheng-Jiang Zhu | Dr. Xiaotao Shen</title>
    <link>https://www.shenxt.info/authors/zheng-jiang-zhu/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.shenxt.info/authors/zheng-jiang-zhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Zheng-Jiang Zhu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Xiaotao Shen 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Reaction Network-based Recursive Metabolite Annotation for Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Large-scale metabolite annotation is a challenge in liquid chromatogram-mass spectrometry (LC-MS)-based untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop a metabolic reaction network (MRN)-based recursive algorithm (MetDNA) that expands metabolite annotations without the need for a comprehensive standard spectral library. MetDNA is based on the rationale that seed metabolites and their reaction-paired neighbors tend to share structural similarities resulting in similar MS2 spectra. MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small library of MS2 spectra, and utilizes their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites, which subsequently serve as the basis for recursive analysis. Using different LC-MS platforms, data acquisition methods, and biological samples, we showcase the utility and versatility of MetDNA and demonstrate that about 2000 metabolites can cumulatively be annotated from one experiment. Our results demonstrate that MetDNA substantially expands metabolite annotation, enabling quantitative assessment of metabolic pathways and facilitating integrative multi-omics analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow an interactive and integrated workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metnormalizer_metabolomics_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metnormalizer_metabolomics_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;availability-and-implementation&#34;&gt;Availability and implementation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MetFlow is freely available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://metflow.zhulab.cn/&#34;&gt;http://metflow.zhulab.cn/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supplementary-information&#34;&gt;Supplementary information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oup.silverchair-cdn.com/oup/backfile/Content_public/Journal/bioinformatics/PAP/10.1093_bioinformatics_bty1066/4/bty1066_supp.docx?Expires=1562370413&amp;amp;Signature=M~uVkc2HM8lV5SS96cccuCh4ZGmq3t5Y3m6X5UCE85GL6tLSiZh5YderYebpfDOwuKWwA9xMxzosXVrwU7f5l314XM6FtEfdChq7YK50O0UReaExGH7LSDTF9yrr0otobCobxejF9MaLttvPhTSV1u2R-~q3n~uqRA-sMZWF2TDaSWo2s-f6E2dknkx5aYgPa56R1MrSbzG1Eu95NCXBGh56Q6-uaCMn6zuwEnzDnKgvONbm0lHjZsO7HhYZJ3evbZ-OsFJiuGpzgpaXoV2OUdL71sCdqm9ebAlPdiNVTGa7T~iUXRBc4vUvmvPcU0eBNoHo3teCF2fC3I0wA03cSQ__&amp;amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAIE5G5CRDK6RD3PGA&#34;&gt;Supplementary data&lt;/a&gt; are available at Bioinformatics online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow an interactive and integrated workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass spectrometry-based metabolomics aims to profile the metabolic changes in biological systems and identify differential metabolites related to physiological phenotypes and aberrant activities. However, many confounding factors during data acquisition complicate metabolomics data, which is characterized by high dimensionality, uncertain degrees of missing and zero values, nonlinearity, unwanted variations and non-normality. Therefore, prior to differential metabolite discovery analysis, various types of data cleaning such as batch alignment, missing value imputation, data normalization and scaling are essentially required for data post-processing. Here, we developed an interactive web server, namely, MetFlow, to provide an integrated and comprehensive workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Correlative Strategy To Discover Colorectal Tumor Tissue Derived Metabolite Biomarkers in Plasma Using Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ac-zhuozhong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ac-zhuozhong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The metabolic profiling of biofluids using untargeted metabolomics provides a promising choice to discover metabolite biomarkers for clinical cancer diagnosis. However, metabolite biomarkers discovered in biofluids may not necessarily reflect the pathological status of tumor tissue, which makes these biomarkers difficult to reproduce. In this study, we developed a new analysis strategy by integrating the univariate and multivariate correlation analysis approach to discover tumor tissue derived (TTD) metabolites in plasma samples. Specifically, untargeted metabolomics was first used to profile a set of paired tissue and plasma samples from 34 colorectal cancer (CRC) patients. Next, univariate correlation analysis was used to select correlative metabolite pairs between tissue and plasma, and a random forest regression model was utilized to define 243 TTD metabolites in plasma samples. The TTD metabolites in CRC plasma were demonstrated to accurately reflect the pathological status of tumor tissue and have great potential for metabolite biomarker discovery. Accordingly, we conducted a clinical study using a set of 146 plasma samples from CRC patients and gender-matched polyp controls to discover metabolite biomarkers from TTD metabolites. As a result, eight metabolites were selected as potential biomarkers for CRC diagnosis with high sensitivity and specificity. For CRC patients after surgery, the survival risk score defined by metabolite biomarkers also performed well in predicting overall survival time (p = 0.022) and progression-free survival time (p = 0.002). In conclusion, we developed a new analysis strategy which effectively discovers tumor tissue related metabolite biomarkers in plasma for cancer diagnosis and prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LipidIMMS Analyzer integrating multi-dimensional information to support lipid identification in ion mobility—mass spectrometry based lipidomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/lipidimms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/lipidimms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the pathological response to neoadjuvant chemoradiation using untargeted metabolomics in locally advanced rectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ro-huixun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ro-huixun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study aimed to identify a panel of potential metabolite biomarkers to predict tumor response to neoadjuvant chemo-radiation therapy (NCRT) in locally advanced rectal cancer (LARC). Liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry (LC–MS)-based untargeted metabolomics was used to profile human serum samples (n=106) from LARC patients treated with NCRT. The samples were collected from Fudan University Shanghai Cancer Center (FUSCC) from July 2014 to January 2016. Statistical methods, such as partial least squares (PLS) and Wilcoxon rank-sum test, were used to identify discriminative metabolites between NCRT-sensitive and NCRT-resistant patients according to their tumor regression grade (TRG). This trial is registered with Clinical Trials.gov, number NCT03149978. A panel of metabolites was selected as potential predictive biomarkers of pathological response to NCRT. A total of 4810 metabolic peaks were detected, and 57 significantly dysregulated peaks were identified. These 57 metabolic peaks were used to differentiate patients using PLS in a dataset containing NCRT-sensitive (n=56) and NCRT-resistant (n=49) patients. The combination of 57 metabolic peaks had AUC values of 0.88, 0.81 and 0.84 in the prediction models using PLS, random forest, and support vector machine, respectively, suggesting that metabolomics has the potential ability to predict responses to NCRT. Furthermore, 15 metabolite biomarkers were identified and used to construct a logistic regression model and explore dysregulated metabolic pathways using untargeted metabolic profiling and data mining approaches. A panel of metabolites has been identified to facilitate the prediction of tumor response to NCRT in LARC, which is promising for the generation of personalized treatment strategies for LARC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LipidCCS Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Lipids with High Precision To Support Ion Mobility–Mass Spectrometry-Based Lipidomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2017-ac-lipidccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2017-ac-lipidccs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of collision cross-section (CCS) values derived from ion mobility–mass spectrometry (IM–MS) has been proven to facilitate lipid identifications. Its utility is restricted by the limited availability of CCS values. Recently, the machine-learning algorithm-based prediction (e.g., MetCCS) is reported to generate CCS values in a large-scale. However, the prediction precision is not sufficient to differentiate lipids due to their high structural similarities and subtle differences on CCS values. To address this challenge, we developed a new approach, namely, LipidCCS, to precisely predict lipid CCS values. In LipidCCS, a set of molecular descriptors were optimized using bioinformatic approaches to comprehensively describe the subtle structure differences for lipids. The use of optimized molecular descriptors together with a large set of standard CCS values for lipids (458 in total) to build the prediction model significantly improved the precision. The prediction precision of LipidCCS was externally validated with median relative errors (MRE) of ∼1% using independent data sets across different instruments (Agilent DTIM-MS and Waters TWIM-MS) and laboratories. We also demonstrated that the improved precision in the predicted LipidCCS database (15,646 lipids and 63,434 CCS values in total) could effectively reduce false-positive identifications of lipids. Common users can freely access our LipidCCS web server for the following (1) the prediction of lipid CCS values directly from SMILES structure; (2) database search; and (3) lipid match and identification. We believe LipidCCS will be a valuable tool to support IM–MS-based lipidomics. The web server is freely available on the Internet (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metabolomics-shanghai.org/LipidCCS/)&#34;&gt;http://www.metabolomics-shanghai.org/LipidCCS/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Metabolites in Ion Mobility-Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metccs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization and integration of large-scale metabolomics data using support vector regression</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
