<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Dr. Xiaotao Shen</title>
    <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication_types/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.shenxt.info/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Xiaotao Shen 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics microsampling for the profiling of lifestyle-associated changes in health</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2023-nbme-microsampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2023-nbme-microsampling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Current healthcare practices are reactive and use limited physiological and clinical information, often collected months or years apart. Moreover, the discovery and profiling of blood biomarkers in clinical and research settings are constrained by geographical barriers, the cost and inconvenience of in-clinic venepuncture, low sampling frequency and the low depth of molecular measurements. Here we describe a strategy for the frequent capture and analysis of thousands of metabolites, lipids, cytokines and proteins in 10 μl of blood alongside physiological information from wearable sensors. We show the advantages of such frequent and dense multi-omics microsampling in two applications, the assessment of the reactions to a complex mixture of dietary interventions, to discover individualized inflammatory and metabolic responses; and deep individualized profiling, to reveal large-scale molecular fluctuations as well as thousands of molecular relationships associated with intra-day physiological variations (in heart rate, for example) and with the levels of clinical biomarkers (specifically, glucose and cortisol) and of physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>massDatabase utilities for the operation of the public compound and pathway database</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-bioinformatics-massdatabase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-bioinformatics-massdatabase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the major challenges in liquid chromatography coupled to mass spectrometry data is converting many metabolic feature entries to biological function information, such as metabolite annotation and pathway enrichment, which are based on the compound and pathway databases. Multiple online databases have been developed. However, no tool has been developed for operating all these databases for biological analysis. Therefore, we developed massDatabase, an R package that operates the online public databases and combines with other tools for streamlined compound annotation and pathway enrichment. massDatabase is a flexible, simple and powerful tool that can be installed on all platforms, allowing the users to leverage all the online public databases for biological function mining. A detailed tutorial and a case study are provided in the Supplementary Material.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision environmental health monitoring by longitudinal exposome and multi-omics profiling</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-gr-exposome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-gr-exposome/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyMass an object-oriented reproducible analysis framework for LC–MS data profiling</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-nc-tidymass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2022-nc-tidymass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility, traceability, and transparency have been long-standing issues for metabolomics data analysis. Multiple tools have been developed, but limitations still exist. Here, we present the tidyMass project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/)&#34;&gt;https://www.tidymass.org/)&lt;/a&gt;, a comprehensive R-based computational framework that can achieve the traceable, shareable, and reproducible workflow needs of data processing and analysis for LC-MS-based untargeted metabolomics. TidyMass is an ecosystem of R packages that share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structure, which provides a comprehensive, reproducible, and object-oriented computational framework. The modular architecture makes tidyMass a highly flexible and extensible tool, which other users can improve and integrate with other tools to customize their own pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metID an R package for automatable compound annotation for LC2MS-based data</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2021-bioinformatics-metid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2021-bioinformatics-metid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accurate and efficient compound annotation is a long-standing challenge for LC–MS-based data (e.g.
untargeted metabolomics and exposomics). Substantial efforts have been devoted to overcoming this obstacle,
whereas current tools are limited by the sources of spectral information used (in-house and public databases) and
are not automated and streamlined. Therefore, we developed metID, an R package that combines information from
all major databases for comprehensive and streamlined compound annotation. metID is a flexible, simple and
powerful tool that can be installed on all platforms, allowing the compound annotation process to be fully automatic
and reproducible. A detailed tutorial and a case study are provided in Supplementary Materials.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Dynamics and Prediction of Gestational Age and Time to Delivery in Pregnant Women</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2020-cell-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2020-cell-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Metabolism during pregnancy is a dynamic and precisely programmed process, the failure of which can bring devastating consequences to the mother and fetus. To define a high-resolution temporal profile of metabolites during healthy pregnancy, we analyzed the untargeted metabolome of 784 weekly blood samples from 30 pregnant women. Using linear models, we built a metabolic clock with five metabolites that time gestational age in high accordance with ultrasound (R = 0.92). Furthermore, two to threemetabolites can identify when labor occurs (time to delivery within two, four, and eight weeks, AUROCR0.85). Our study represents a weekly characterization of the human pregnancy metabolome, providing ahigh-resolution landscape for understanding pregnancy with potential clinical utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Reaction Network-based Recursive Metabolite Annotation for Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-nc-metdna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Large-scale metabolite annotation is a challenge in liquid chromatogram-mass spectrometry (LC-MS)-based untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop a metabolic reaction network (MRN)-based recursive algorithm (MetDNA) that expands metabolite annotations without the need for a comprehensive standard spectral library. MetDNA is based on the rationale that seed metabolites and their reaction-paired neighbors tend to share structural similarities resulting in similar MS2 spectra. MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small library of MS2 spectra, and utilizes their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites, which subsequently serve as the basis for recursive analysis. Using different LC-MS platforms, data acquisition methods, and biological samples, we showcase the utility and versatility of MetDNA and demonstrate that about 2000 metabolites can cumulatively be annotated from one experiment. Our results demonstrate that MetDNA substantially expands metabolite annotation, enabling quantitative assessment of metabolic pathways and facilitating integrative multi-omics analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow an interactive and integrated workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2019-bioinformatics-metflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mass spectrometry-based metabolomics aims to profile the metabolic changes in biological systems and identify differential metabolites related to physiological phenotypes and aberrant activities. However, many confounding factors during data acquisition complicate metabolomics data, which is characterized by high dimensionality, uncertain degrees of missing and zero values, nonlinearity, unwanted variations and non-normality. Therefore, prior to differential metabolite discovery analysis, various types of data cleaning such as batch alignment, missing value imputation, data normalization and scaling are essentially required for data post-processing. Here, we developed an interactive web server, namely, MetFlow, to provide an integrated and comprehensive workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Correlative Strategy To Discover Colorectal Tumor Tissue Derived Metabolite Biomarkers in Plasma Using Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ac-zhuozhong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ac-zhuozhong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The metabolic profiling of biofluids using untargeted metabolomics provides a promising choice to discover metabolite biomarkers for clinical cancer diagnosis. However, metabolite biomarkers discovered in biofluids may not necessarily reflect the pathological status of tumor tissue, which makes these biomarkers difficult to reproduce. In this study, we developed a new analysis strategy by integrating the univariate and multivariate correlation analysis approach to discover tumor tissue derived (TTD) metabolites in plasma samples. Specifically, untargeted metabolomics was first used to profile a set of paired tissue and plasma samples from 34 colorectal cancer (CRC) patients. Next, univariate correlation analysis was used to select correlative metabolite pairs between tissue and plasma, and a random forest regression model was utilized to define 243 TTD metabolites in plasma samples. The TTD metabolites in CRC plasma were demonstrated to accurately reflect the pathological status of tumor tissue and have great potential for metabolite biomarker discovery. Accordingly, we conducted a clinical study using a set of 146 plasma samples from CRC patients and gender-matched polyp controls to discover metabolite biomarkers from TTD metabolites. As a result, eight metabolites were selected as potential biomarkers for CRC diagnosis with high sensitivity and specificity. For CRC patients after surgery, the survival risk score defined by metabolite biomarkers also performed well in predicting overall survival time (p = 0.022) and progression-free survival time (p = 0.002). In conclusion, we developed a new analysis strategy which effectively discovers tumor tissue related metabolite biomarkers in plasma for cancer diagnosis and prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LipidIMMS Analyzer integrating multi-dimensional information to support lipid identification in ion mobility—mass spectrometry based lipidomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-bioinformatics-lipidimms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-bioinformatics-lipidimms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the pathological response to neoadjuvant chemoradiation using untargeted metabolomics in locally advanced rectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ro-huixun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2018-ro-huixun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study aimed to identify a panel of potential metabolite biomarkers to predict tumor response to neoadjuvant chemo-radiation therapy (NCRT) in locally advanced rectal cancer (LARC). Liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry (LC–MS)-based untargeted metabolomics was used to profile human serum samples (n=106) from LARC patients treated with NCRT. The samples were collected from Fudan University Shanghai Cancer Center (FUSCC) from July 2014 to January 2016. Statistical methods, such as partial least squares (PLS) and Wilcoxon rank-sum test, were used to identify discriminative metabolites between NCRT-sensitive and NCRT-resistant patients according to their tumor regression grade (TRG). This trial is registered with Clinical Trials.gov, number NCT03149978. A panel of metabolites was selected as potential predictive biomarkers of pathological response to NCRT. A total of 4810 metabolic peaks were detected, and 57 significantly dysregulated peaks were identified. These 57 metabolic peaks were used to differentiate patients using PLS in a dataset containing NCRT-sensitive (n=56) and NCRT-resistant (n=49) patients. The combination of 57 metabolic peaks had AUC values of 0.88, 0.81 and 0.84 in the prediction models using PLS, random forest, and support vector machine, respectively, suggesting that metabolomics has the potential ability to predict responses to NCRT. Furthermore, 15 metabolite biomarkers were identified and used to construct a logistic regression model and explore dysregulated metabolic pathways using untargeted metabolic profiling and data mining approaches. A panel of metabolites has been identified to facilitate the prediction of tumor response to NCRT in LARC, which is promising for the generation of personalized treatment strategies for LARC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LipidCCS Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Lipids with High Precision To Support Ion Mobility–Mass Spectrometry-Based Lipidomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2017-ac-lipidccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2017-ac-lipidccs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of collision cross-section (CCS) values derived from ion mobility–mass spectrometry (IM–MS) has been proven to facilitate lipid identifications. Its utility is restricted by the limited availability of CCS values. Recently, the machine-learning algorithm-based prediction (e.g., MetCCS) is reported to generate CCS values in a large-scale. However, the prediction precision is not sufficient to differentiate lipids due to their high structural similarities and subtle differences on CCS values. To address this challenge, we developed a new approach, namely, LipidCCS, to precisely predict lipid CCS values. In LipidCCS, a set of molecular descriptors were optimized using bioinformatic approaches to comprehensively describe the subtle structure differences for lipids. The use of optimized molecular descriptors together with a large set of standard CCS values for lipids (458 in total) to build the prediction model significantly improved the precision. The prediction precision of LipidCCS was externally validated with median relative errors (MRE) of ∼1% using independent data sets across different instruments (Agilent DTIM-MS and Waters TWIM-MS) and laboratories. We also demonstrated that the improved precision in the predicted LipidCCS database (15,646 lipids and 63,434 CCS values in total) could effectively reduce false-positive identifications of lipids. Common users can freely access our LipidCCS web server for the following (1) the prediction of lipid CCS values directly from SMILES structure; (2) database search; and (3) lipid match and identification. We believe LipidCCS will be a valuable tool to support IM–MS-based lipidomics. The web server is freely available on the Internet (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metabolomics-shanghai.org/LipidCCS/)&#34;&gt;http://www.metabolomics-shanghai.org/LipidCCS/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Metabolites in Ion Mobility-Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/first_corresponding_article/2016-ac-metccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/first_corresponding_article/2016-ac-metccs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of metabolomics has significantly advanced health and disease related research. However, metabolite identification remains a major analytical challenge for untargeted metabolomics. While the use of collision cross-section (CCS) values obtained in ion mobility-mass spectrometry (IM-MS) effectively increases identification confidence of metabolites, it is restricted by the limited number of available CCS values for metabolites. Here, we demonstrated the use of a machine-learning algorithm called support vector regression (SVR) to develop a prediction method that utilized 14 common molecular descriptors to predict CCS values for metabolites. In this work, we first experimentally measured CCS values (ΩN2) of ∼400 metabolites in nitrogen buffer gas and used these values as training data to optimize the prediction method. The high prediction precision of this method was externally validated using an independent set of metabolites with a median relative error (MRE) of ∼3%, better than conventional theoretical calculation. Using the SVR based prediction method, a large-scale predicted CCS database was generated for 35,203 metabolites in the Human Metabolome Database (HMDB). For each metabolite, five different ion adducts in positive and negative modes were predicted, accounting for 176,015 CCS values in total. Finally, improved metabolite identification accuracy was demonstrated using real biological samples. Conclusively, our results proved that the SVR based prediction method can accurately predict nitrogen CCS values (ΩN2) of metabolites from molecular descriptors and effectively improve identification accuracy and efficiency in untargeted metabolomics. The predicted CCS database, namely, MetCCS, is freely available on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Metabolites in Ion Mobility-Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2016-ac-metccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2016-ac-metccs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of metabolomics has significantly advanced health and disease related research. However, metabolite identification remains a major analytical challenge for untargeted metabolomics. While the use of collision cross-section (CCS) values obtained in ion mobility-mass spectrometry (IM-MS) effectively increases identification confidence of metabolites, it is restricted by the limited number of available CCS values for metabolites. Here, we demonstrated the use of a machine-learning algorithm called support vector regression (SVR) to develop a prediction method that utilized 14 common molecular descriptors to predict CCS values for metabolites. In this work, we first experimentally measured CCS values (ΩN2) of ∼400 metabolites in nitrogen buffer gas and used these values as training data to optimize the prediction method. The high prediction precision of this method was externally validated using an independent set of metabolites with a median relative error (MRE) of ∼3%, better than conventional theoretical calculation. Using the SVR based prediction method, a large-scale predicted CCS database was generated for 35,203 metabolites in the Human Metabolome Database (HMDB). For each metabolite, five different ion adducts in positive and negative modes were predicted, accounting for 176,015 CCS values in total. Finally, improved metabolite identification accuracy was demonstrated using real biological samples. Conclusively, our results proved that the SVR based prediction method can accurately predict nitrogen CCS values (ΩN2) of metabolites from molecular descriptors and effectively improve identification accuracy and efficiency in untargeted metabolomics. The predicted CCS database, namely, MetCCS, is freely available on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Metabolites in Ion Mobility-Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/preprint/2016-ac-metccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/preprint/2016-ac-metccs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of metabolomics has significantly advanced health and disease related research. However, metabolite identification remains a major analytical challenge for untargeted metabolomics. While the use of collision cross-section (CCS) values obtained in ion mobility-mass spectrometry (IM-MS) effectively increases identification confidence of metabolites, it is restricted by the limited number of available CCS values for metabolites. Here, we demonstrated the use of a machine-learning algorithm called support vector regression (SVR) to develop a prediction method that utilized 14 common molecular descriptors to predict CCS values for metabolites. In this work, we first experimentally measured CCS values (ΩN2) of ∼400 metabolites in nitrogen buffer gas and used these values as training data to optimize the prediction method. The high prediction precision of this method was externally validated using an independent set of metabolites with a median relative error (MRE) of ∼3%, better than conventional theoretical calculation. Using the SVR based prediction method, a large-scale predicted CCS database was generated for 35,203 metabolites in the Human Metabolome Database (HMDB). For each metabolite, five different ion adducts in positive and negative modes were predicted, accounting for 176,015 CCS values in total. Finally, improved metabolite identification accuracy was demonstrated using real biological samples. Conclusively, our results proved that the SVR based prediction method can accurately predict nitrogen CCS values (ΩN2) of metabolites from molecular descriptors and effectively improve identification accuracy and efficiency in untargeted metabolomics. The predicted CCS database, namely, MetCCS, is freely available on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization and integration of large-scale metabolomics data using support vector regression</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2016-metabolomics-metnormalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2016-metabolomics-metnormalizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Untargeted metabolomics studies for biomarker discovery often have hundreds to thousands of human samples. Data acquisition of large-scale samples has to be divided into several batches and may span from months to as long as several years. The signal drift of metabolites during data acquisition (intra- and inter-batch) is unavoidable and is a major confounding factor for large-scale metabolomics studies. We aim to develop a data normalization method to reduce unwanted variations and integrate multiple batches in large-scale metabolomics studies prior to statistical analyses. We developed a machine learning algorithm-based method, support vector regression (SVR), for large-scale metabolomics data normalization and integration. An R package named MetNormalizer was developed and provided for data processing using SVR normalization. After SVR normalization, the portion of metabolite ion peaks with relative standard deviations (RSDs) less than 30 % increased to more than 90 % of the total peaks, which is much better than other common normalization methods. The reduction of unwanted analytical variations helps to improve the performance of multivariate statistical analyses, both unsupervised and supervised, in terms of classification and prediction accuracy so that subtle metabolic changes in epidemiological studies can be detected. SVR normalization can effectively remove the unwanted intra- and inter-batch variations, and is much better than other common normalization methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serum metabolomics for early diagnosis of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma by UHPLC-QTOF/MS</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Previous metabolomics studies have revealed perturbed metabolic signatures in esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) patients, however, most of these studies included mainly late-staged ESCC patients due to the difficulties of collecting the early-staged samples from asymptotic ESCC subjects. Objectives This study aims to explore the early-staged ESCC metabolic signatures and potential of serum metabolomics to diagnose ESCC at early stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Serum samples of 97 ESCC patients (stage 0, 39 cases; stage I, 17 cases; stage II, 11 cases, stage III, 30 cases)
and 105 healthy controls (HC) were enrolled and randomly separated into training data (77 ESCCs, 84 HCs) and validation
data (20 ESCCs, 21 HCs). Untargeted metabolomics was performed to identify ESCC-related metabolic signatures.
Results The global metabolomics profiles could clearly distinguish ESCC from HC in training data. 16 ascertained
metabolites were found to be disturbed in the metabolic pathways characterized by dysregulated fatty acid biosynthesis,
glycerophospholipid metabolism, choline metabolism in cancer and linoleic acid metabolism. The AUC value in validation data was 0.895, with sensitivity 85.0 % and specificity 90.5 %. Good diagnostic performances were also achieved for early stage ESCC, with the values of area under the curve (AUC) 0.881 for the ESCC patients in both stage 0 and I–II. In addition, six metabolites were found to discriminate ESCC stages. Among them, three
biomarkers, dodecanoic acid, LysoPA(18:1), and LysoPC(14:0), exhibited clear trend for ESCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: These findings suggest serum metabolomics, performed in a minimally noninvasive and convenient
manner, may possess great potential for early diagnosis of ESCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
