<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metabolomics | Dr. Xiaotao Shen</title>
    <link>https://www.shenxt.info/tags/metabolomics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.shenxt.info/tags/metabolomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Metabolomics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Xiaotao Shen 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Dynamics and Prediction of Gestational Age and Time to Delivery in Pregnant Women</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2020-cell-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/2020-cell-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetNormalizer</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metnormalizer-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metnormalizer-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;MetNormalizer&lt;/code&gt; is used to normalize large scale metabolomics data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deepPseudoMSI</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/deeppseudomsi-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/deeppseudomsi-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;deepPseudoMSI&lt;/code&gt; project is the first method that convert LC-MS raw data to “images” and then process them using deep learning method for diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metID</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metid-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metid-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;metID&lt;/code&gt; is a R packge which is used for metabolite identification based on in-house database and public database based on accurate mass, rentention time and/or MS2 spectra.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyMass</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/tidymass-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/tidymass-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;TidyMass&lt;/code&gt; project is a comprehensive computational framework that can process the whole workflow of data processing and analysis for LC-MS-based untargeted metabolomics using tidyverse principles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Correlative Strategy To Discover Colorectal Tumor Tissue Derived Metabolite Biomarkers in Plasma Using Untargeted Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/zhuozhong_ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/zhuozhong_ac/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the pathological response to neoadjuvant chemoradiation using untargeted metabolomics in locally advanced rectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/huixun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/huixun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study aimed to identify a panel of potential metabolite biomarkers to predict tumor response to neoadjuvant chemo-radiation therapy (NCRT) in locally advanced rectal cancer (LARC). Liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry (LC–MS)-based untargeted metabolomics was used to profile human serum samples (n=106) from LARC patients treated with NCRT. The samples were collected from Fudan University Shanghai Cancer Center (FUSCC) from July 2014 to January 2016. Statistical methods, such as partial least squares (PLS) and Wilcoxon rank-sum test, were used to identify discriminative metabolites between NCRT-sensitive and NCRT-resistant patients according to their tumor regression grade (TRG). This trial is registered with Clinical Trials.gov, number NCT03149978. A panel of metabolites was selected as potential predictive biomarkers of pathological response to NCRT. A total of 4810 metabolic peaks were detected, and 57 significantly dysregulated peaks were identified. These 57 metabolic peaks were used to differentiate patients using PLS in a dataset containing NCRT-sensitive (n=56) and NCRT-resistant (n=49) patients. The combination of 57 metabolic peaks had AUC values of 0.88, 0.81 and 0.84 in the prediction models using PLS, random forest, and support vector machine, respectively, suggesting that metabolomics has the potential ability to predict responses to NCRT. Furthermore, 15 metabolite biomarkers were identified and used to construct a logistic regression model and explore dysregulated metabolic pathways using untargeted metabolic profiling and data mining approaches. A panel of metabolites has been identified to facilitate the prediction of tumor response to NCRT in LARC, which is promising for the generation of personalized treatment strategies for LARC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Prediction of Collision Cross-Section Values for Metabolites in Ion Mobility-Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metccs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/metccs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetDNA</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metdna-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metdna-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small tandem spectral library, and utilize their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites which are subsequently served as the basis for recursive analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetFlow</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metflow-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/project/metflow-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed an interactive web server, namely, MetFlow, to provide an integrated and comprehensive workflow for metabolomics data cleaning and differential metabolite discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization and integration of large-scale metabolomics data using support vector regression</title>
      <link>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shenxt.info/publication/journal-article/taozhang_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
